Nicholas Roosevelt Papers
Nicholas Roosevelt Papers
circa 1720-1987
Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1893-1982.
49.75 linear ft.
The correspondence, memorabilia, and writings of journalist and diplomat Nicholas Roosevelt
149551
Biographical History
Nicholas Roosevelt (1893-1982) was an American author, journalist, conservationist, and diplomat.
Roosevelt was born June 12, 1893, in New York City. Nicholas's father, James West Roosevelt, was the first cousin of President Theodore Roosevelt. Nicholas received his A.B. from Harvard in 1914. He served as an attaché at the American Embassy in Paris for the next two years, and as secretary to the American mission to Spain in 1916-1917. In the 1920s he was a foreign correspondent and editorial writer for The New York Times. In 1926, Roosevelt wrote and published a book, The Philippines, A Treasure and a Problem, in which he argued against the United States granting the Philippines independence on the grounds that Filipinos were incapable of governing their own affairs. In 1930, President Herbert Hoover appointed Roosevelt to serve as Vice-Governor to the Philippines, but he was released from the post after a few months due to nation-wide protests by Filipinos, who were upset about Roosevelt's depiction of their country and people. Shortly after he left his post in the Philippines he was named minister to Hungary, a post he held for three years (1930-1933).
Roosevelt returned to journalism once he came home from Hungary. He was a member of the Council on Foreign Relations and a writer for its journal Foreign Affairs, and an editorial writer for the New York Herald Tribune, where he was deeply critical of President Franklin D. Roosevelt and his administration. A life-long Republican, Nicholas Roosevelt criticized the New Deal and big government policies.
In addition to his newspaper work, Roosevelt wrote twelve books including A New Birth of Freedom (1938), Venezuela's Place in the Sun: Modernizing a Pioneering Country (1940), Creative Cooking (1956), and Theodore Roosevelt: The Man as I Knew Him (1967). His autobiography, A Front Row Seat, was published in 1953.
Roosevelt retired from journalism in 1946 due to ill health and moved to Big Sur, California. Inspired by an Arizona trip he took in 1913 with his cousin, Theodore Roosevelt (an avid conservationist), Roosevelt became heavily involved in conservationist movements. He was active in the Save-the-Redwoods League and served on California's recreation commission. In 1970, he published Conservation: Now or Never, an appeal for the conservation of Earth's resources.
Roosevelt died February 16, 1982, in Monterey, California.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Nicholas Roosevelt Papers consists of Correspondence-subject files, Financial and legal material, Memorabilia, and Writings.
Correspondence-subject files reflects Roosevelt's status as a diplomat and journalist who was involved in both American and foreign politics. Roosevelt exchanged correspondence with a variety of politicians, including President Herbert Hoover, whom Roosevelt served as minister to Hungary within his administration. There are also several folders of correspondence with President Theodore Roosevelt, the majority of which is between Theodore Roosevelt and Nicholas's mother, Laura. Laura and Theodore were good friends as well as cousins by marriage. There is also correspondence with the extended Roosevelt family, including President Franklin D. Roosevelt and First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt. Other material relates to Nicholas's books, including letters regarding progress and comments about the book. Incomplete correspondence or correspondence with illegible names are listed last in the series.
Financial and legal files consists of a small number of book contracts, a lease contract for a boat, expense accounts for a trip to Asia, and a folder of miscellaneous financial items such as invoices and receipts.
Memorabilia consists of clippings, diaries, photographs, postcards, scrapbooks, and other assorted items. Clippings are primarily newspaper clippings of Roosevelt's writings for various newspapers. There are also clippings of reviews of Roosevelt's books. His diaries cover his many travels around the world. One diary to note is that of his trip in Arizona with former President Theodore Roosevelt in the summer of 1913, in which he shares stories regarding the popular President. Also included in this series are the family papers of Roosevelt's mother, Laura D'Oremieulx Roosevelt. The majority of these papers were originally stored in a box with a label that read, "D'Oremieulx-Gibbs records and letters," and therefore have been kept together under that heading. Scrapbooks primarily consist of newspaper clippings of reviews of Nicholas's books, articles and editorials that he wrote, or trips that he took. Other items of note include a program for a reception for Theodore Roosevelt after his return from Cuba fighting with the Rough Riders during the Spanish American War; an oral history of Roosevelt's memories of working with Herbert Hoover; and photographs of Nicholas Roosevelt, as well as a photograph of Theodore Roosevelt.
Writings includes articles, books, book reviews, editorials, letters to the editor, reflections, and speeches. Most of the articles are from Roosevelt's time as a foreign correspondent and editorialist for The New York Times and the New York Herald Tribune, and as a reporter for foreign newspapers. Material for his books includes drafts, corrections, galleys, manuscripts, notes, and research. Books that have significant material in the collection are: Creative Cooking (1956), Economic Forces in the Development of American History (1951), A Front Row Seat (1953), Good Cooking (1959), A New Birth of Freedom (1939), Stream of Liberty (1954), and Theodore Roosevelt: The Man as I Knew Him (1967). Book reviews are by Roosevelt for books written by other authors. Editorials are from his time as an editor for The New York Times and the New York Herald Tribune. Personal narratives and reflections include an account of the Republican Convention of 1912, at which former President Theodore Roosevelt unsuccessfully challenged sitting President William Howard Taft for the Republican nomination for President. Speeches include notes and transcripts of speeches and lectures throughout his career as a diplomat and journalist. At the end of the series are a few miscellaneous items such as the draft of a book chapter for an unpublished book, some notes, and a poem, and a few pieces by others.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically by name or topic, apart from Roosevelt's diaries, which are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; New York State; Politics, government and public administration; Activism and social reform; Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951.; Albright, Horace M. (Horace Marden), 1890-1987.; Atchley, Dana W. (Dana Winslow), 1892-1982.; Churchill, Winston, 1874-1965.; Clemenceau, Georges, 1841-1929.; Colby, William Egan, 1920-1996.; Dulles, Allen, 1893-1969.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.; Eisenhower, Milton Stover, 1899-1985.; Feis, Herbert, 1893-1972.; Finley, John H. (John Huston), 1863-1940.; Gilbert, Prentiss Bailey.; Grew, Joseph C. (Joseph Clark), 1880-1965.; Gunther, John, 1901-1970.; Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-1964.; Hanfstaengl, Ernst, 1887-1975.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.; Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; Krock, Arthur, 1886-1974.; Lamont, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1870-1948.; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1902-1985.; Lottinville, Savoie, 1906-1997.; Lucas, Dione, 1909-1971.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959.; Mayo, Katherine, 1868?-1940.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Moley, Raymond, 1886-1975.; Montgomery, John Fleshman, 1905-; Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971.; Osborne, Lithgow, 1892-1980.; Reinhardt, Aurelia Henry, 1877-1948.; Robinson, Edgar Eugene, 1887-1977.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Roosevelt, Archibald, 1918-1990.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D., Jr. (Franklin Delano), 1914-1988.; Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1893-1982.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944.; Roosevelt family.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979.; Sansom, George Bailey, Sir, 1883-1965.; Schuyler, Louisa Lee.; Seldes, George, 1890-1995.; Shirer, William L. (William Lawrence), 1904-1993.; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950.; Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1891-1968.; Toynbee, Arnold, 1889-1975.; Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1846-1926.; Warner, Langdon, 1881-1955.; Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.; Authors, American.; Conservationists -- United States.; Cooking.; Diplomats -- United States.; Journalists -- United States.; National parks and reserves -- United States.; Nature conservation -- United States.; Arizona -- Description and travel.; United States -- Diplomatic and consular service -- Hungary.; United States -- Diplomatic and consular service -- Philippines.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Hungary.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Philippines.; United States -- Foreign relations -- 1929-1933.; United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Articles.; Book reviews.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Dispatches.; Drafts (documents); Editorials.; Galley proofs.; Genealogies (histories); Lectures.; Manuscripts for publication.; Oral histories (literary works); Photographs.; Programs (documents); Scrapbooks.; Speeches (documents); Authors.; Conservationists.; Diplomats.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Abbot, Willis J., 1928; 1930 (Box 1)
  - Abend, Hallett, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Academie de Paris, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ansel, 1950; 1953-1954,; 1956,; 1970 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Brooks, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Charles F. III, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Adams, J. Donald, 1956-1958 (Box 1)
  - Adams, James Truslow, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Akers-Douglas, Aretas, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Albright, Horace Marden, 1930; 1946,; 1951-1953,; 1959-1960,; 1967-1969,; 1972 (Box 1)
  - Alemany, Jose E., 1930 (Box 1)
  - Alsop, Joseph and Corinne, 1910; 1927,; 1930,; 1947-1948,; 1956,; 1964 (Box 1)
  - America and England, 1930 (Box 1)
  - American Commission to Negotiate Peace, 1919 (Box 1)
  - American Expeditionary Forces, 1918-1919 (Box 1)
  - American Meat Institute, 1955; 1957 (Box 1)
  - American-Hungarian Foundation, 1930 (Box 1)
  - American Newspaper Publishers Association, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Ames, Charles Lesley, 1941; 1954 (Box 1)
  - Andrew, A. Platt, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Aponyi, Albert, 1930; 1933 (Box 1)
  - Arizona Pioneers' Historical Association, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Armament Limitation Conference, Washington, DC, 1921-1922 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Atchley, Dana W., 1954; 1956,; undated (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Union Committee, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Auld, George P., 1930 (Box 1)
  - Austria, 1923; 1932-1933 (Box 64)
  - A, miscellaneous, 1927-1959 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Robert L., 1930 (Box 1)
  - Baer, J.A., 1930 (Box 1)
  - Bain, H. Foster, 1928; 1930 (Box 1)
  - Baker, George Barr, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Hanson W., 1958 (Box 1)
  - Balzer, Robert L., 1956 (Box 1)
  - Bank for International Settlements, 1931-1933; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Batchelder, Charles C., 1927; 1930 (Box 1)
  - Beebe, Lucius, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Benedikt, Ernst, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Bernhard, George, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Berton, Claude, 1921-1926 (Box 1)
  - Bessie, Simon Michael, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bingham, Hiram, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Birchall, Frederick T., 1933 (Box 1)
  - Bird, Remsen D., 1953 (Box 1)
  - Blair, Floyd, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Blake, Tiffany, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Blankenstein, Marcus van, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Bliss, Robert Woods and Mildred, 1932; 1953-1954,; 1960 (Box 1)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1955; 1957,; undated (Box 1)
  - Blum, John M., 1955 (Box 1)
  - Book requests, 1946; Roosevelt's requests for books for research; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Borah, William E., 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - Boswell, Helen Varick, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Bouton, S. Miles, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Bowers, Claude G., 1926 (Box 2)
  - Bowmann, Isaiah, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Brashears, Edward, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Bristol, Mark Lambert, 1928 (Box 2)
  - British Legation Budapest, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Edmund G., 1962; 1965 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Helen Evans, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Philip Marshall, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Brownell, George A., 1930; 1932 (Box 2)
  - Bruce, William Cabell, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Burlingame, Roger, 1950; 1953 (Box 2)
  - Burnham, John B., 1938 (Box 2)
  - Buxton, G. Edward Jr., 1947 (Box 2)
  - Byers, Horace R., 1950 (Box 2)
  - B, miscellaneous, 1918-1965 (Box 2)
  - California Conservation Council, 1948 (Box 2)
  - California Department of Fish and Game, 1964 (Box 2)
  - California Department of Natural Resources, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - Campbell Soup Company, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry S., 1953 (Box 2)
  - Cape, Jonathan, LTD, undated (Box 2)
  - Carter, John Ridgely, 1914; 1932,; 1953 (Box 2)
  - De Cartier De Marchienne, Emile-Ernest, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Castle, William R. Jr., 1925-1932 (Box 2)
  - The Century Association, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Chandler, Lewis Stuyvesant, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
  - Chandler, Norman, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Channing, Edward, 1915 (Box 2)
  - Charles Scribner and Sons, 1928; 1932-1933,; 1938,; 1950,; 1953 (Box 2)
  - Chenery, William Ludlow, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Chevalier, John B., 1930 (Box 2)
  - Churchhill, Winston, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Clark, J. Reuben Jr., 1938 (Box 2)
  - Clemenceau, Georges, 1895; 1923 (Box 2)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Climate in Europe, 1930 (Box 64)
  - Cobb, Henry E., 1930 (Box 2)
  - Colby, Francis T., 1919 (Box 2)
  - Colby, William Edward, 1944-1946; 1953,; 1959 (Box 2)
  - Colby College, 1956; 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Coolidge, Archibald Cary, 1919; 1921; 1925; 1927 (Box 2)
  - Coolidge, Harold Jefferson Jr., 1973 (Box 2)
  - Conservation: now or never, correspondence and materials related to Roosevelt's book
    See also Memorabilia: Scrapbook: Conservation: Now or never.
    - California Department of Parks and Recreation, 1961-1963; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - California Department of Parks and Recreation, 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Cape Cod, 1968 (Box 3)
    - The Conservation Law Society of America, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Dodd, Mead and Company, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Feedback, 1970-1972; comments and congratulations from friends (Box 3)
    - Grand Canyon, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Gustafson, Carl O., 1963 (Box 3)
    - Hetch Hetchy [Yosemite National Park], 1967 (Box 3)
    - Highways, 1966-1968 (Box 3)
    - Iowa, 1968; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Monterey Peninsula College, 1962-1971 (Box 3)
    - National parks, 1926; 1950 (Box 3)
    - Nelson, Dewitt, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Niagara Power Plant, 1963 (Box 3)
    - Storm King Mountain on the Hudson River, 1967-1968; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Storm King Mountain on the Hudson River, 1967-1969; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - United States Department of Agriculture Forest Service, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - United States Department of the Interior, Bureau of Outdoor Recreation, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - Wilderness Society, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Yosemite, 1928; 1967 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1967 (Box 4)
  - Corbin, John, 1923 (Box 4)
  - Cotterman, C.N., 1926-1930 (Box 4)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1928-1933 (Box 4)
  - Cowles, Anna "Bamie" Roosevelt, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Cowles, L. Sheffield, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Cox, James M., 1929; 1956-1957 (Box 4)
  - Creative cooking, 1956; correspondence related to Roosevelt's book (Box 4)
    See also Writings: Books: Creative cooking.
  - Creel, George, 1919 (Box 4)
  - C, miscellaneous, 1923-1966 (Box 4)
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Dana, Samuel T., 1959 (Box 4)
  - Darling, J.N. "Ding", 1930 (Box 4)
  - Davie, Eugenie Mary "May" Ladenburg, 1938; 1954 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Adelle, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Dwight F., 1930 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Elmer, 1949; 1951,; 1953 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Lavinia R., 1953 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Norman H., 1932-1933 (Box 4)
  - Dawes, Charles G., 1931 (Box 4)
  - Dawson, Geoffrey, 1924; 1926,; 1930 (Box 4)
  - Delano, William Adams, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Derby, Ethel Carow Roosevelt, 1927; 1930,; 1948,; 1965,; 1975 (Box 4)
  - Desmond, Thomas C., 1938 (Box 4)
  - Disarmament, 1922; 1930 (Box 4)
  - Dodd, Mead and Company, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Donath, Leo, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Doubleday and Company, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Dougherty, Dennis Joseph, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Douglas, Lewis Williams, 1933 (Box 5)
  - Draper, Arthur S., 1929 (Box 5)
  - Dryfoos, Orvil E., 1944-1946; 1948,; 1953,; 1957-1960 (Box 5)
  - Duckworth-Ford, R.A., 1930-1931 (Box 5)
  - Duer, Edward Rush, 1931-1933 (Box 5)
  - Duggan, Stephen P., 1926 (Box 5)
  - Dulles, Allen W., 1919; 1933,; 1938,; 1952 (Box 5)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Dunn, Gano, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Durand, E. Dana, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Dutch Anti-War Council, 1915 (Box 5)
  - D, miscellaneous, 1920-1962 (Box 5)
  - Edge, Walter E., 1933 (Box 5)
  - Eisenhower, Milton S., 1953 (Box 5)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1946; 1948,; 1955 (Box 5)
  - Evans, Arthur H., 1929 (Box 5)
  - Fairchild, George H., 1926 (Box 5)
  - Farnol, Lynn, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Farquhar, Francis P., 1956 (Box 5)
  - Far East trip, 1925-1926 (Box 5)
  - Farr, Fred S., 1962 (Box 5)
  - Feis, Herbert, 1931-1932 (Box 5)
  - Finley, John H., 1930-1931; 1945 (Box 5)
  - Fischer, Arthur F., 1926; 1930-1931 (Box 5)
  - Fisher, Harold H., 1949; 1955,; undated (Box 5)
  - Fisk, Harvey Edward, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Flavin, Martin, 1953; 1956 (Box 5)
  - Fletcher, Henry Prather, 1933 (Box 5)
  - Ford, R. A. Duckworth, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1927; 1932,; 1954 (Box 5)
  - A front row seat, 1953 (Box 5)
    See also Writings: Books: A front row seat.
  - Fullerton, William Morton, 1928; 1933 (Box 5)
  - E-F, miscellaneous, 1928-1968 (Box 5)
  - Gammack and Company, 1931 (Box 5)
  - Gannett, Lewis, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Gardiner, William Howard, 1928-1932 (Box 5)
  - Garrett, John W., 1928-1933; 1955 (Box 5)
  - General Electric Company, 1955; 1958 (Box 5)
  - Gerard, Paul, 1951 (Box 5)
  - Gift acknowledgements, 1962; 1971,; 1981 (Box 5)
  - Gilbert, Newton W., 1930 (Box 6)
  - Gilbert, Prentiss B., 1930-1933 (Box 6)
  - Gilbert, Rodney, 1928 (Box 6)
  - Gilmore, Eugene Allen, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Gilmore, Melvin R., 1929-1932 (Box 6)
  - Goddard, Jack, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Gordon, George A., 1933 (Box 6)
  - Grant, Madison, 1930-1931 (Box 6)
  - Green, Joseph E., 1919; 1931-1932,; 1939 (Box 6)
  - Green, Theodore Francis, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Greene, Winthrop S., 1931 (Box 6)
  - Gregor, Joseph, 1931 (Box 6)
  - Grey, Edward, 1928 (Box 6)
  - Griffin, Allen, 1949; 1953,; 1966 (Box 6)
  - Gruenberger, Alfred, 1930 (Box 6)
  - Gunther, John, 1931-1933; 1956,; 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - G, miscellaneous, 1925-1959 (Box 6)
  - Habsburg, Otto Von, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann, 1923-1924; 1930,; 1950-1959 (Box 6)
  - Hanfstaengl, Ernst F.S., 1930 (Box 6)
  - Harbord, James Gutherie, 1927-1930 (Box 6)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1956-1960; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Harvard Alumni Association, 1954-1955 (Box 6)
  - Harvard Alumni Bulletin, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Haussermann, John W., 1930 (Box 6)
  - Havas, Eugene, 1932-1933; 1966 (Box 6)
  - Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1927 (Box 6)
  - Hayes, John S., 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - Hays, William Harrison, 1927; 1931 (Box 6)
  - Heiser, Victor G., 1926; 1930 (Box 6)
  - Henning, Arthur S., 1929 (Box 6)
  - Herter, Christian, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Hilles, Charles D., 1934 (Box 6)
  - Hills, Lawrence, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Hodgman, William A., 1931-1933 (Box 7)
  - Hodgson, Caspar W., 1929 (Box 7)
  - Hollister, Paul M., 1966 (Box 7)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1927-1940; 1974 (Box 7)
  - Hornbeck, Stanley, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Horthy, Nicholas, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Houghton, Amory, 1951 (Box 7)
  - House and Garden, 1959-1960; correspondence with the magazine (Box 7)
  - Howard, Shafter L., 1938 (Box 7)
  - Howe, Louis, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Howell, G. C. L., 1932 (Box 7)
  - Hubbel, J. L., 1913; 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - Hubble, Edwin, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Hume, Edward Hicks, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Humphrey, Grace, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Hungarian American Chamber of Commerce, 1932 (Box 7)
  - Hungarian American Society, 1933-1937 (Box 7)
  - Hungary
    - Appointment as minister to Hungary, 1930 (Box 64)
    - Financial condition, 1924; 1928-1932; 4 folders (Box 64)
    - Foreign bonds in the United States, 1932-1933 (Box 64)
    - Legation, 1932-1933 (Box 64)
    - Resignation, 1933 (Box 64)
    - United States and, 1932-1933; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Hunt, George T., 1963 (Box 7)
  - Hunter, Gordon C., 1933 (Box 7)
  - Huntington Library and Art Gallery, San Marino, CA, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Hurley, Patrick Jay, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - Huxley, Julian, 1930 (Box 7)
  - H, miscellaneous, 1923-1960 (Box 7)
  - Institute of American History, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Institute of International Education, 1931-1932 (Box 7)
  - Irvine, Cecelia, 1954-1956 (Box 7)
  - Irving Trust Company, 1932 (Box 7)
  - Isaacs, Stanley M., 1926; 1930 (Box 7)
  - Janssen, Werner, 1932 (Box 7)
  - Jenkins, Louisa Meyer, undated (Box 7)
  - Johns Hopkins Press, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Gerald White, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Harold B., 1935 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Nelson Trusler, 1926-1928 (Box 7)
  - Jones, Hilary Pollard, Jr., 1928-1929 (Box 7)
  - Jones, Thomas Jessee, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Jusserand, Jean Jules, 1914 (Box 7)
  - I-J, miscellaneous, 1926-1957 (Box 7)
  - Kaltenborn, H.V., 1930 (Box 7)
  - Kandel, I.L., 1946 (Box 8)
  - Karo, George, 1931 (Box 8)
  - Kean, Katherine Winthrop, 1927 (Box 8)
  - Kellogg, Frank B., 1928-1929 (Box 8)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1960 (Box 8)
  - Kennedy, Sinclair, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Kinney, Henry W., 1951 (Box 8)
  - Klebelsberg, Kuno von, 1931 (Box 8)
  - Kleeman, Rita Halle, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Klein, Julius, 1931 (Box 8)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., 1954 (Box 8)
  - Knox, Frank, 1932 (Box 8)
  - Kraus, Lili, 1951 (Box 8)
  - Krehbiel, Henry E., 1922 (Box 8)
  - Krock, Arthur, 1930-1932; 1950,; 1953,; 1956-1957 (Box 8)
  - K, miscellaneous, 1927-1979 (Box 8)
  - La Follette, Philip, 1930; 1933,; 1956 (Box 8)
  - La Follette, Robert M., Jr., 1939 (Box 8)
  - De La Llana, Pedro, 1930-1932 (Box 4)
  - La Mont, Thomas S., 1925; 1928,; 1932,; 1939 (Box 8)
  - Landon, Alf M., 1935; 1938 (Box 8)
  - Lawrence, David, 1929 (Box 8)
  - League of Nations, 1931-1933 (Box 64)
  - League of Nations, 1925; 1927,; 1931-1933; 9 folders (Box 65)
  - Lee, Ivy Ledbetter, 1931 (Box 8)
  - Legation of the United States Belgrade, 1932 (Box 8)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, undated (Box 8)
  - Library of Congress, Copyright Office, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Lim, Vicente, 1928 (Box 8)
  - Lingnan University, 1926 (Box 8)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1930-1931 (Box 8)
  - Little, Brown and Company, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1932; 1939 (Box 8)
  - Loeb, William, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Long Island Rail Road Company, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1930; 1938,; 1956 (Box 8)
  - Lottinville, Savoie, 1952-1960 (Box 8)
  - Lowe, Belle, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Lowell, A. Lawrence, 1914; 1938 (Box 8)
  - Lucas, Dione, 1956-1958 (Box 8)
  - Luce, Henry R., 1933 (Box 8)
  - Lunt, Carroll, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Lyon, Frederick B., 1932 (Box 8)
  - L, miscellaneous, 1929-1978 (Box 8)